This demo uses an AI-generated narration voice.
For many Deaf and hard-of-hearing people, a
simple phone-only task can become a barrier.
SayAhead lets the user read, guide, and control the conversation.
It is a supervised, text-first calling assistant.
The user sets the destination, goal, facts
that may be shared, and hard boundaries.
The assistant handles the conversation, but the user keeps final control.
Here, Maya wants to reserve a quiet library room.
She approves only the minimum facts the assistant needs
and forbids fees, payments, or new personal details.
She confirms that this is a user-initiated, low-risk call.
For reliable public judging, this site deliberately simulates the GPT-5.6 planning
stages and uses the same structured contract without external credentials.
In configured mode, the OpenAI Responses API uses GPT-5.6 Sol
to turn approved facts and boundaries into a reviewable plan.
Nothing happens before review.
Maya can check the objective, conversation path,
success criteria, and every approval gate.
The opening identifies SayAhead’s AI accessibility assistant and asks affirmative
consent to continue with live transcription and temporary text review.
What you are about to see is a public demo simulation;
it does not place a phone call.
The Twilio and OpenAI Realtime path is implemented and
has been tested with a consented, allowlisted destination.
Rather than pressure the person answering with a checklist, the
assistant explains that it is helping someone use live captions,
asks one warm consent question, and then uses the plan
to make reasonable low-risk choices while keeping the exchange natural.
Maya can pause without speaking, type what SayAhead should
say, correct a detail, resume, or end the call.
Large two-speaker captions clearly separate the person answering from the
assistant, so she can follow the conversation at a glance.
When the library offers the room, the assistant stops.
Nothing is committed until Maya chooses.
Payments, emergencies, marketing, and high-stakes medical or financial calls are blocked entirely;
this first release stays deliberately low risk.
After the call, Maya gets confirmed details, the reference
number, next actions, and the full conversation for review.
In configured mode, GPT-5.6 structures this outcome.
SayAhead does not record or store audio;
the text remains only in this browser
tab and can be cleared explicitly.
Codex helped me implement and test the accessible React interface,
safety guardrails, GPT-5.6 integration, and the Twilio-to-OpenAI Realtime bridge.
SayAhead turns phone calls into conversations the
user can read, guide, and control.